Hello. I'm Dr. Michael Clarkson. Welcome to
大家好。我是迈克尔·克拉克森博士。欢迎来到《OCaml函数式编程》。
Functional Programming in OCaml. My main job
is teaching university students to write correct,
我的主要工作是教授大学生编写正确、高效且优美的程序。在过去的几年里，我在康奈尔大学教授了大约3700名学生。
efficient, and beautiful programs. In the last
few years, I've taught OCaml to about 3 ,700
我的主要工作是教授大学生编写正确、高效且优美的程序。在过去的几年里，我在康奈尔大学教授了大约3700名学生。
students at Cornell University in a course
这门课程名为CS3110，《数据结构与函数式编程》。
titled CS3110, Data Structures and Functional
Programming.
这门课程名为CS3110，《数据结构与函数式编程》。
You might have come across this video in any
你可能是以多种方式接触到这个视频的。也许你现在就是康奈尔大学CS3110课程的学生。也许你不是康奈尔学生，但你想学习一些函数式编程的知识。
number of ways. Maybe you're actually a student
in CS 3110 right now. Maybe you're not a
你可能是以多种方式接触到这个视频的。也许你现在就是康奈尔大学CS3110课程的学生。也许你不是康奈尔学生，但你想学习一些函数式编程的知识。
Cornell student, but you're looking to learn
something about functional programming. Maybe
你可能是以多种方式接触到这个视频的。也许你现在就是康奈尔大学CS3110课程的学生。也许你不是康奈尔学生，但你想学习一些函数式编程的知识。
you came here from the online textbook in
也许你是从嵌入了这段视频的在线教材中来的，或者只是单纯地想了解一些关于函数式编程的内容。
which this video is embedded, or maybe you
found the video first. In which case, check
我先找到了视频。在这种情况下，请查看下方评论以获取当前的链接到课本。
the comments below for the current link to
the textbook. I've been writing the textbook
我一直都在编写这本教材，已有数年时间。它是基于我自己和其他教员过去二十多年撰写的课程笔记。
for a few years now. It's based on course
notes written by myself and other faculty for
我一直都在编写这本教材，已有数年时间。它是基于我自己和其他教员过去二十多年撰写的课程笔记。
over two decades. Beyond teaching functional
我们的目标不仅仅是教授函数式编程，还希望培养出优秀的程序员，让他们掌握成功所需的知识、技能和习惯，而不仅仅局限于基础的计算机科学入门课程。
programming, our goal has long been to teach
students to be great programmers, to equip
我们的目标不仅仅是教授函数式编程，还希望培养出优秀的程序员，让他们掌握成功所需的知识、技能和习惯，而不仅仅局限于基础的计算机科学入门课程。
them with the knowledge, skills, and habits
they need to be successful beyond the basics
我们的目标不仅仅是教授函数式编程，还希望培养出优秀的程序员，让他们掌握成功所需的知识、技能和习惯，而不仅仅局限于基础的计算机科学入门课程。
of the usual introductory computer science classes.
These videos, however, are new. They came about
然而，这些视频是新的。它们是因为疫情才产生的。在2020年至2021年的学年里，我教授了这门课的异步版本。
because of pandemic. In the 2020 through 2021
academic  year,
然而，这些视频是新的。它们是因为疫情才产生的。在2020年至2021年的学年里，我教授了这门课的异步版本。
I taught an asynchronous version of my class.
That meant these videos had to replace the
这意味着这些视频必须替代传统的面对面讲座。因此我制作了超过200个短片，大多数时长在5到6分钟之间。
usual in -person lectures. So I ended up producing
over 200 short videos, most around five to
学生的反应非常积极。现在，我将这些视频公开发布给任何想要了解OCaml、函数式编程以及成为更好程序员的人。
six minutes in length. And the reaction from
students was overwhelmingly positive. So now
他们的反馈让我感到非常欣慰。我希望你发现它们有用，甚至有趣。它们是我对所有在Zoom U时期坚持下来的同学们的爱的告白。我们共同度过了那段时光。现在，当我们传播函数式编程之光时，也许世界会变得更好一些。
I'm making the videos publicly available for
anyone who wants to learn something about OCaml,
他们的反馈让我感到非常欣慰。我希望你发现它们有用，甚至有趣。它们是我对所有在Zoom U时期坚持下来的同学们的爱的告白。我们共同度过了那段时光。现在，当我们传播函数式编程之光时，也许世界会变得更好一些。
functional programming, and becoming a better
programmer.
他们的反馈让我感到非常欣慰。我希望你发现它们有用，甚至有趣。它们是我对所有在Zoom U时期坚持下来的同学们的爱的告白。我们共同度过了那段时光。现在，当我们传播函数式编程之光时，也许世界会变得更好一些。
I hope you find them useful, maybe even entertaining.
希望你发现它们有用，甚至有趣。
They are a love letter for me to all the
students who endured through the time of Zoom
U. We did it together. And now, maybe the
world can be just a bit better as we spread
the  light  of  functional  programming.